Inventory of the John Boyd Bentley Papers, 1895-1987
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Oversize, 1914-1985.
  - Medium Oversize, 1914-1985.
    Mostly diplomas and certificates of Bishop Bentley and Mrs. Bentley, including Mrs. Bentley's high school diploma, United Daughters of the Confederacy (UDC) and Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR) membership certificates, and Bishop Bentley's certificates as Deacon, Priest, and Bishop, honorary degrees, and items received in Japan (written in Japanese) in 1949. Also photograph of Bracken House in Williamsburg, where the Bentleys resided, 1929-1939.
  - Oversize, 1916-1985., 3 items.
    Items include a photograph of Battery D, 1st Regiment of Field Artillery, Virginia Volunteers, at Richmond, 27 June 1916, honorary degree from College of William and Mary (1985), and copy of the "Frenchman's Map" of Williamsburg.
  Series 5: Artifacts
- Artifacts, 1958-1970. (Box-folder A:1-15)
  - Photograph (rolled) of delegates to 1958 Lambeth Conference, also includes key to photograph, 1958., Photograph. (Box A)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award Plaque, College of William and Mary, presented to Bentley, 8 June 1942., Plaque. (Box-folder A:1)
  - The Jessen's Weekly Annual Award (Plaque) for Distinguished Service to Alaska, presented to Bentley, 1948., Plaque. (Box-folder A:2)
  - Belt buckle with Bentley's name inscribed on it by Private Harry E. Black, Battery "B", 111th Field Artillery, while billeted in Rosieres-Sur-Mance, France, Winter of 1918-1919., Belt buckle. (Box-folder A:3)
  - Book board from unidentified leather-bound book, bearing the book plate of Bentley's ancestor, John Boyd. (Box-folder A:4)
  - Cross given to Bentley by his classmates at the Virginia Seminary when he left for Alaska, May 1921., Cross. (Box-folder A:5)
  - Cross given to Bentley by the Missionary District of Alaska on the 15th anniversary of Bentley's consecration as Bishop, 1946., Cross. (Box-folder A:6)
  - Cross given to Bentley by the Diocese of Southern Virginia, n.d., Cross. (Box-folder A:7)
  - "Housewife" made for Bentley by Margaret M. Sims when he was called up for active service, June 1916, and used during World War I. (Box-folder A:8)
    Also includes pocket-size New Testament, inscribed by Margaret M. Sims.
  - Medal for Service and Loyalty to the College of William and Mary, awarded in 1970., Medal. (Box-folder A:9)
  - Alumni Rosette, College of William and Mary. (Box-folder A:10)
  - Painting of Alaskan landscape by Mrs. John W. Chapman given to Elvira Bentley on her birthday, 15 February 1922., Painting. 3" x 5" (Box-folder A:11)
  - Fraternity ring for Kappa Alpha., Ring. (Box-folder A:12)
  - Wallet for travel documents belonging to Bishop Bentley., Wallet. (Box-folder A:13)
    Documents previously kept in it are in personal items files.
  - Wallet for travel documents belonging to Elvira C. Bentley., Wallet. (Box-folder A:14)
    Documents previously kept in it removed and filed with personal items.
  - Army identification tag, inscribed "John B. Bentley, 1st Lt., III F.A., U.S.A." (Box-folder A:15)
  Series 6: Audio Cassettes
- Audio cassettes of autobiography, 1900-1964, and sermon preached in Wren Chapel, 1984; 1900-1964, 1984., Audio cassettes. (Othertype 1-9)
  - Audio cassette entitled "A description of Hampton Creek about 1900, with a brief outline of my life from my birth until I went to Richmond with Battery "D" in 1916," 1900-1916., Audio cassette. (Othertype 1)
  - Audio cassette, 1989-1915., Audio cassette. (Othertype 2)
    Side 1 is entitled "A description of Hampton Creek about 1900, and my story until 1898."
    Side 2 is entitled "My year in the Shipyard, 1914-1915."
  - Audio cassette, 1916-1921., Audio cassette. (Othertype 3)
    Side 1 is entitled "My military career from June, 1916, until we left Camp de Meucon, France in October, 1918."
    Side 2 is entitled "Our last days in France, our return to the U.S.A., and all that happened from then until we arrived at Anvik, Alaska in 1921."
  - Audio cassette entitled "Anvik, 1921-1925"; "Charlotte Hall School, 1925-1926"; and "my appointment with Dr. Goodwin about going to Williamsburg," 1921-1926., Audio cassette. (Othertype 4)
  - Audio cassette, 1926-1931., Audio cassette. (Othertype 5)
    Side 1 is entitled "Williamsburg, 1926-1930."
    Side 2 is entitled "Winter Journey, 1930-1931," and "Summer Journey, 1931."
  - Audio cassette, 1931-1932., Audio cassette. (Othertype 6)
    Side 1 is entitled "Consecration in Denver, September 29, 1931."
    Side 2 is entitled "Voyage of PELICAN IV, 1932," and "Revival of The Alaskan Churchman."
  - Audio cassette entitled "1931-1947," 1931-1947., Audio cassette. (Othertype 7)
  - Audio cassette entitled "Years at the office in New York, 1948-1964.", Audio cassette. (Othertype 8)
  - A sermon preached in the chapel of the Wren Building, September 30, 1984., Audio cassette. (Othertype 9)
  Series 7: Addition 1994.90
- One cassette of interviews with Bishop John Boyd Bentley (W&M, 1915-1916, 1919-1921) and Carter Henry Harrison (W&M, 1920-1923) 1915-1923, 1989., 1 item. (Othertype 1994.90)
  Interviews were aired during 1989 as part of the "Virginia Voices" series on WHRO-FM public radio. Both were interviewed by Tempy Cornelius-Fisk.